Finding Aid for Emmet O. Allen papers, 1867-1931
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Emmet O. Allen papers 1867-1931
Allen, Emmet O. (Emmet Oliver), 1846-1933.
1 linear ft.
85588 Aa 2
Emmet O. and Elizabeth Howell Allen family of Bridgewater Township, Washtenaw County, Michigan. Correspondence concerning daily activities and pioneer life in Kansas and Clinton, Michigan.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was the gift of Mildred Allen (donor no. 4831 ) and came to the library in 1971.
The collection is open to research.
Emmet O. Allen was born May 24, 1846 in Bridgewater Township, Washtenaw County, Michigan. His family had recently moved from New York State. He attended a rural school close to his home, also a school at Clinton and Ypsilanti, Michigan. As a young man, he lived in Kansas for a time, but then came back to Michigan. In 1881, he married Elizabeth (Libbie) Howell. Both he and his wife were teachers.
This family collection is divided into the following series: William F. Allen; Emmet O. Allen; Elizabeth Howell Allen; Matthew Howell; and Photographs
Subjects:
Bridgewater (Mich.: Township); Clinton (Mich.); Farm life--Michigan--Washtenaw County.; Kansas.; Washtenaw County (Mich.); Women in agriculture--Michigan--Washtenaw County.
Contributors:
Allen, Elizabeth Howell.; Linden, Judson.
Genre Terms:
Photographs
- William F. Allen
  (father of Emmet O. Allen)
  - Letters to his brother Oliver Allen of East Bethany, Genesee County, New York, 1841-1857 (Box 1)
    (the letters are written from Tecumseh and Clinton)
- Emmet O. Allen
  - Reminiscences, letters, and essays, 1867-1875, photocopy (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1860-1931 and undated, 12 folders (Box 1)
    (some gaps in dates)
  - Letters from friend Judson Linden, 1872-1888, 3 folders; include some transcriptions of letters (Box 1)
    (most of the letters written from Kansas)
- Elizabeth Howell Allen
  - Correspondence, 1868-1936 and undated, 11 folders (Box 1)
    (the letters are from friends and family members)
  - Essays, 1869-1900 and undated, 2 folders (Box 1)
- Matthew Howell
  (Matthew Howell was the father of Elizabeth Howell and lived near Saline, in Clinton and Adrian, Michigan)
  - Letter received, 1846-1898 (Box 1)
- Photographs
  - Portraits of family members (Box 1)